Guide to the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union Collection WAG.329
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Southern Tenant Farmers' Union Collection
1930-1989
1972-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Southern Tenant Farmers' Union
Mitchell, Samuel
Mitchell, Dorothy Dowe
WAG.329
10 Linear Feet in 8 record cartons, 2 oversize flat boxes and 1 manuscript box.
The Southern Tenant Farmers' Union (STFU) was founded in 1934, in Tyronza, Arkansas by an interracial assembly of eighteen local sharecroppers and tenant farmers. Despite extreme persecution by landowners and deputy sheriffs the movement quickly developed locals in communities throughout the delta region and beyond. The STFU numbered 31,000 members at its peak in 1938. Several agricultural strikes and two roadside encampments-highlighting the plight of agricultural workers-garnered national press coverage. State commissions were established to relieve the plight of sharecroppers in Arkansas and neighboring Missouri and federal legislation was passed, creating programs to underwrite loans for sharecroppers to buy their own farms, as well as programs to build emergency housing for agricultural laborers. This collection consists of several hundred slide photographs, approximately ninety audio cassettes, sixty video cassettes, a dozen reel to reel tapes and a dozen 16mm films. The slides document sharecroppers, STFU leaders and rank-and-file members, and the devastation in Depression-era Dust Bowl farms. The film, video and reel to reel tape recording were generated in the course of filming the documentary "Our Land Too" on the history of the STFU.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Southern Tenant Farmers' Union was founded in 1934, in Tyronza, Arkansas, a rural town in northeast Arkansas. The region up until the 1930s was fertile and impoverished, consisting primarily of cotton plantations own by a small number of land owners. Sharecroppers, tenant farmers, and agricultural laborers worked the land. Sharecroppers were provided seed, tools, a shack to live in and credit to buy food and clothing. They turned over half their crop to the landowner. Tenant farmers provided their own tools and seed, turning over one third of their crop to the landowner. Agricultural laborers worked the landowners' land for small wages.
The New Deal agricultural subsidy programs redistributed income towards the landowners, at the expense of the sharecroppers and laborers working the land. With this miscarriage of policy as their impetus, H.L. Mitchell and Henry Clay East, two self-taught socialists, who ran a laundry and filing station respectively, in Tyronza, began talking up socialist alternatives to the agricultural system in operation in much of the Arkansas delta. The first meeting of the STFU, on July 13th 1934, was attended by an interracial assembly of eighteen local sharecroppers and tenant farmers.
Despite extreme persecution by landowners and deputy sheriffs the STFU quickly developed locals in communities throughout the delta region and beyond. The STFU numbered 31,000 members at its peak in 1938, and parleyed support from socialist leader Norman Thomas, Eleanor Roosevelt, Rheinhold Niebuhr, Gardner Jackson (working in 1934 for the Department of Agriculture), and others to obtain the ear of federal agricultural policy makers.
Enduring shootings, beating and near-lynchings, the STFU obtained a great deal of press coverage. A "March of Time" newsreel was made in 1935 about sharecroppers. Several agricultural strikes and two roadside encampments-highlighting the plight of agricultural workers-garnered national press coverage. State commissions were established to relieve the plight of sharecroppers in Arkansas and neighboring Missouri and federal legislation was passed: the STFU influenced the creations of programs to underwrite loans for sharecroppers to buy their own farms, and to build emergency housing for agricultural laborers.
The STFU is also memorable for the quasi-religious character the movement assumed. The union had its own anthems and fighting songs ("Roll the Union On," was composed by STFU member John Handcox). It had elaborate rituals: "The Ceremony of the Land," and a string-tying initiation ceremony. Principles of racial equality were espoused from the beginning of the STFU, making it one of the first interracial organizations of working people to function in the southern United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of several hundred slide photographs, approximately ninety audio cassettes, sixty video cassettes, a dozen reel to reel tapes and a dozen 16mm films. The slides document sharecroppers, Southern Tenant Farmers' Union (STFU) leaders and rank-and-file members, and the devastation in Depression-era Dust Bowl farms. Prominent photographers such as Margaret Bourke-White, Dorothea Lange and Farm Security Administration photographers are included. Audio cassette recordings include a small number of interviews with STFU organizers as well as lectures given by H.L. Mitchell and others at U.S. college campuses. The film, video and reel to reel tape recording were generated in the course of filming the documentary "Our Land Too" on the history of the STFU.
Related Archival Materials
Print materials from the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union are owned by the Southern Rural Welfare Association, Inc., and are on loan to The Southern Historical Collection of the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Library:
Southern Tenant Farmers' Union Records, 1931-1991 (Collection #03472)
The papers of Henry Clay East, co-founder of the STFU, were donated to the University of Arkansas Libraries Special Collections in 1973:
Henry Clay East Papers (Collection 189)
Custodial History
Film, video and reel to reel tapes were commissioned by Southern Tenant Farmers' Union founder H.L. Mitchell, who also headed the Southern Rural Welfare Assocation, Inc. until his death in 1989. Many of these materials were produced by Kudzu Films of Montgomery, Alabama, though rights to these materials were held by H.L. Mitchell. Audio recordings were primarily made by H.L. Mitchell.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Initially donated by Micky Beth Stiller on behalf of Dorothy Dowe Mitchell in 1991. A new donation agreement was signed by Sam Mitchell (H.L. Mitchell's son) in 2009. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1990.001, 1990.002, 1990.004, 1990.007, and NPA.2005.173.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series:
Series I: Slides, 1934-1985
Series II: Audio Recordings, 1930-1985
Series III: Film and Video Recordings, 1978-1989
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Audiovisual materials that have not been preserved are not available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Oklahoma; Missouri; Videocassettes.; Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |z United States.; Arkansas; Migrant labor -- United States; Migrant agricultural laborers |x Labor unions; Cotton picking |z United States; Agricultural laborers |x Labor unions |x Organizing; Depressions -- 1929.; 16mm; Audiocassettes.; Slides (photographs); Tennessee; East, Henry Clay, 1900-; Mitchell, H. L. (Harry Leland), 1906-1989; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.); Mitchell, Samuel; Mitchell, Dorothy Dowe
- Series I: Slides, 1936-1985
  - Carousel #1, 1935-1947 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Carousel #2, 1934-1958 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Carousel #3, 1936-1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Carousel #4, 1935-1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Duplicates, 1934-1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: STFU 50th Anniversary, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Series II: Audio Recordings, 1930-1985
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 2)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 3)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 4)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 6)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 7)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 8)
  - Anniversary, 48th: Joe Glazer Songs, Apr 16, 1982-Apr 17, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 9)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 17, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 11)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 17, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 12)
  - Anniversary, 48th, Apr 17, 1982 (Box 1, Reel 13)
  - Anniversary, 48th: Mae White, Philip Vera Cruz, Anne Loftis, Lorna Beury, Sister Anne Catherine), Apr 17, 1982; cuid245 (Box 1, Reel 14, Box 12, Cd Reel 14)
  - Handcox, John: Folk Songs (Library of Congress), undated (Box 1, Reel 15)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: "The Mind of the South 1972" Lecture, Mar 5, 1972 (Box 1, Reel 16)
  - Kestler, Howard; John Handcox: "Raggedy Are We," "Roll the Union On" and "In my Heart;" Clay East, Apr 2, 1972; undated (Box 1, Reel 17)
  - National Public Radio; 50th Anniversary (Little Rock, AK), Mar 16, 1984 (Box 1, Reel 18)
  - Blank, undated (Box 1, Reel 19)
  - Migratory Labor Hearings, U.S. Senate (Washington D.C.), 1952 (Box 1, Reel 21)
  - Migratory Labor Hearings, U.S. Senate (Washington, D.C.) [reel 22], 1952 (Box 1, Reel 22)
  - Folk Songs from the Library of Congress, undated (Box 1, Reel 23)
  - WSPA News (Spartanburg, S.C.), [Nov 1973] (Box 1, Reel 24)
  - Handcox, John: Songs, undated (Box 1, Reel 25)
  - Organization of American Historians No. 6: Disruptive Elements in Southern Agriculture, undated (Box 13, Cassette C1)
  - Organization of American Historians No. 6B: Disruptive Elements in Southern Agriculture, undated (Box 13, Cassette C2)
  - Unknown ("Reel 1"), 1930/1950 (Box 13, Cassette C3)
  - Thomas, Norman: Princeton, Nov 9, 1984 (Box 13, Cassette C4)
  - Radicalism, Mar 1, 1977 (Box 13, Cassette C8)
  - Booker-Partlove, Charles Dover, undated (Box 13, Cassette C9)
  - Unknown, undated (Box 13, Cassette C10)
  - Hartman, Joel: Rusual Sociology, University of Montana, Jan 16, 1977 (Box 13, Cassette C12A)
  - Waslow: Labor Education, University of Montana, Oct 26, 1977 (Box 13, Cassette C12B)
  - Secretary STFU Assoc, undated (Box 13, Cassette C17)
  - Campbell, Mitchell: Basic Issues in Land Reform Opening Remarks, undated (Box 13, Cassette C20)
  - Rural Revolt (KSU-SU), Oct 13, 1975 (Box 13, Cassette C22)
  - SP-LA May Day, undated (Box 13, Cassette C32)
  - AFL-CIO (ARK Hot Springs), Jun 5, 1979 (Box 13, Cassette C40)
  - Real, Deacy (Seattle), Apr 6, 1974; cuid261 (Box 13, Cassette C53A, Box 12, Cd C53A)
  - Clark, Booker (Seattle), Apr 6, 1974; cuid246 (Box 13, Cassette C53B, Box 12, Cd C53B)
  - Rand, Jimbo, undated (Box 13, Cassette C61)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: Miami University, undated (Box 13, Cassette C64)
  - Handcox, John L.: Home Cooking in San Diego, 1981 (Box 13, Cassette C66)
  - NPR and Proceeding, 50th STFU, undated (Box 13, Cassette C67A)
  - Provedeer, Choco, Apr 15, 1981; cuid247 (Box 13, Cassette C74, Box 12, Cd C74)
    Scope and Contents
    Original recording had loud ambient noise throughout which makes some parts inaudible
  - Fickle: MSU, Oct 6, 1975 (Box 13, Cassette C78)
  - Lapapolen family, Jul 31, 1984; cuid248 (Box 13, Cassette C90, Box 12, Cd C90)
  - Pelet, Henry, Jul 31, 1984; cuid249 (Box 13, Cassette C91A, Box 12, Cd C91A)
  - Pelet, William Rhodes, Jul 31, 1984; cuid250 (Box 13, Cassette C91B, Box 12, Cd C91B)
  - Rhodes, William, Jul 31, 1984; cuid251 (Box 13, Cassette C92, Box 12, Cd C92)
  - Acorn, Ralkke: Interview on H.L. Mitchell Article, undated (Box 13, Cassette C97)
  - Rodgers, Ward A: SWL History - NCRA and Farm Workers, undated (Box 13, Cassette C103)
  - Earl (SP), Apr 25, 1974 (Box 13, Cassette C108)
  - Clay, East: University of New Mexico, Apr 13, 1975 (Box 13, Cassette C109)
  - Clay, East, Apr 13, 1975 (Box 13, Cassette C110)
  - Sharecroppers, undated; cuid252 (Box 13, Cassette C113A, Box 12, Cd C113A)
  - Thomas, Norman: At Birdsong, undated; cuid262 (Box 13, Cassette C113B, Box 12, Cd C113B)
  - Thomas, Norman: Letters, Apr 27, 1935 (Box 13, Cassette C114A)
  - Thomas, Norman: End, Oct 4, 1935 (Box 13, Cassette C114B)
  - Johnson, Clyde, Apr 29, 1976; cuid253 (Box 13, Cassette C118, Box 12, Cd C118A-B)
  - Johnson, Clyde, Apr 29, 1976; cuid254 (Box 13, Cassette C119, Box 12, Cd C119)
  - Johnson, Clyde, Apr 27, 1976; cuid255 (Box 13, Cassette C120, Box 12, Cd C120)
  - Johnson, Clyde, Apr 27, 1976; cuid256 (Box 13, Cassette C121, Box 12, Cd C121)
  - Osanaich, Ruth: STFU Letter to Son, Apr 25, 1974 (Box 13, Cassette C126)
  - Pelet, Rhode: LCH, undated (Box 13, Cassette C134)
  - Wonderful People I've Known, undated (Box 14, Cassette C137)
  - "For Mitch", Sep 25, 1974 (Box 14, Cassette C138)
  - Kester, Howard: Funeral, Jul 14, 1977 (Box 14, Cassette C140)
  - Stith, George, Apr 26, 1973; cuid257 (Box 14, Cassette C143, Box 12, Cd C143)
  - New Mexico, undated (Box 14, Cassette C162)
  - Unknown ("Tape 1"), undated (Box 14, Cassette C171)
  - Jacskon, Gardner (Jr), Apr 15, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C181)
  - Jacskon, Gardner (Jr), Apr 15, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C182)
  - Jacskon, Gardner (Jr), Apr 15, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C183)
  - Jacskon, Gardner (Jr), Apr 15, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C184)
  - Booker, Fannye, Apr 16, 1982; cuid258 (Box 14, Cassette C185, Box 12, Cd C185)
  - Franklin, Sam H (Rev), Apr 17, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C186)
  - Davis, Tee (Mrs), Apr 16, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C187)
  - Schlesinger, undated (Box 14, Cassette C190A)
  - Schlesinger, undated (Box 14, Cassette C190B)
  - Gilbert, Jess and Don Holley: New Deal in the South, undated (Box 14, Cassette C191A)
  - Holley, Don and John Zippert, Apr 16, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C191B)
  - Friday, Apr 16, 1982; cuid263 (Box 14, Cassette C195A)
  - Handcox, John, undated; cuid259 (Box 14, Cassette C195B, Box 12, Cd C195B)
  - Weiss, Nancy and Sheldon Hackney: Princeton, Apr 4, 1973 (Box 14, Cassette C255A)
  - Rutger, Alexander, Apr 4, 1973 (Box 14, Cassette C255B)
  - Kent State, Oct 25, 1972 (Box 14, Cassette C260A)
  - Akron University, Oct 26, 1972 (Box 14, Cassette C260B)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara, Apr 22, 1975 (Box 14, Cassette C266)
  - Appalacian State University, Boone, NC, Oct 12, 1972 (Box 14, Cassette C282A)
  - Appalacian State University, Boone, NC, Oct 13, 1972 (Box 14, Cassette C282B)
  - Trout, Charles: Mount Holyoke, Oct 28, 1974 (Box 14, Cassette C283)
  - Benstrow: New South and Sociology, UAB Lecture, undated (Box 14, Cassette C402)
  - Benstrow: New South and Sociology, UAB Lecture, undated (Box 14, Cassette C404)
  - Highlarder: SS Meet, undated (Box 14, Cassette C407A)
  - Notes for Unknown Meeting, undated (Box 14, Cassette C407B)
  - Union and Clergy, Oct 12, 1980 (Box 14, Cassette C409)
  - Notes from STFU Papers, Courses on Wealth, undated (Box 14, Cassette C422)
  - Tenor, Halle and H.L. Mitchell, Sep 30, 1982 (Box 14, Cassette C434)
  - Butler, JR, Apr 15, 1975 (Box 14, Cassette C435A)
  - East, Joe: ESM, Apr 16, 1975 (Box 14, Cassette C435B)
  - Bonache, Rolande: South West History, undated (Box 14, Cassette C441)
  - Mercer, Jun 24, 1974 (Box 14, Cassette C449)
  - Goodwyn, Larry: Seminar, Jan 31, 1975 (Box 14, Cassette C450)
  - Unknown, Apr 14, 1985 (Box 14, Cassette C451)
  - Duncan, Karl, Apr 21, 1971; cuid260 (Box 14, Cassette C452, Box 12, Cd C452)
  - University of Louisville, Oct 23, 1972 (Box 14, Cassette C453A)
  - Berea, Oct 24, 1972 (Box 14, Cassette C453B)
  - History Clarree, WNK, undated (Box 14, Cassette C454)
  - Unknown, undated (Box 14, Cassette C455A)
  - SWL Farm Labor Dance, Mar 4, 1977 (Box 14, Cassette C455B)
  - Spealon, MD (KMPL Radio), Feb 24, 1980 (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C456)
  - Out Panel SCM, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C457)
  - Moto, AK, May 4, 1978 (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C471)
  - Lapeyrolerie, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C472)
  - Unknown, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C473)
  - Unknown, Aug 17, 1976 (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C475A)
  - Dunberg, Aug 13, 1976 (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C475B)
  - Cope Report, AFL/CIO, May 1, 1971 (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1301)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1302)
  - Unknown ("No Good"), undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1303)
  - Rondan, Jack, Oct 27, 1985 (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1304)
  - Unknown, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1305)
  - Handcox, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1306A)
  - Seeger, Pete, undated (Box Shared Cassette Box 5, Cassette C1306B)
  - Coreil, Jules: Transcript, Feb 3, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: Transcript, Jan 23, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Stanfield, Charles: Transcript, Jan 4, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Series III: Film and Video Recordings, 1978-1989 (Box 3 (Master DVDs))
  - Very Rony, Arthur Schlesinger Jr. ("Cannister #1"), undated (Box 7, Reel 1-6)
  - STFU Outtakes ("Cannister #2"), undated (Box 7, Reel 1-6)
  - Burgess, Dave ("Roll 3") [2 reels], undated (Box 8, Reel 3)
  - STFU ("Roll 5"), undated (Box 9, Reel 5)
  - STFU ("Roll 6"), undated (Box 8, Reel 6)
  - STFU ("Roll 8"), undated (Box 8, Reel 8)
  - "Our Land Too" [answer print], circa 1987 (Box 10)
  - Handcox, John: Interview [film transfer], Apr 16, 1982 (Box 10)
  - H.L. Mitchell and Mae K. White: "Out of the Past Comes the Future" (OPCF), [1986] (Box 2, Video 1)
  - Ward Rogers and David Burgess: "OPCF", [1986] (Box 2, Video 2)
  - Preachers' Story: About Holding Back Cotton ("OPCF"), [1986] (Box 2, Video 3)
  - H.L. Mitchell: "OPCF", [1986] (Box 2, Video 4)
  - H.L. Mitchell: "OPCF", [1986] (Box 2, Video 5)
  - Migrant Workers: "OPCF", [1986] (Box 2, Video 6)
  - Anniversary, 48th (Excerpts), undated (Box 2, Video 7)
  - Mean Things Happening in This Land, undated (Box 2, Video 8)
  - KETC TV: Affirmative Action; 50th Anniversary of Sharecroppers Protest, Feb 14, 1989 (Box 2, Video 9)
  - Southern Radical #1, undated (Box 2, Video 11)
  - Southern Radical #2, #3 and #4, undated (Box 2, Video 12)
  - Southern Radical #3, undated (Box 3, Video 13)
  - McNeil Lehrer; 1939 Sharecroppers Demonstration; KETC TV Affirmative Action and 50th Anniversary of Sharecroppers Protest, Feb 14, 1989 (Box 3, Video 14)
  - "Ending the Silence: Civil Disobedience in the Farm Crisis"; "In the Shadow of War"; "Women of the Earth"; Deep Dish TV, undated (Box 3, Video 15)
  - "Our Land Too" Promotion, undated (Box 3, Video 18)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: Lecture, undated (Box 3, Video 19)
  - Mitchell: Photographs, Jan 10, 1986 (Box 3, Video 20)
  - "A Tenant Farmer Remembers", Nov 10, 1979 (Box 3, Video 21)
  - Mitchell: Founder of First Tenant Farmers Union (WMC TV 5, Memphis), Oct 31, 1978 (Box 3, Video 22)
  - Cleselia's Story: Organized Migration Program; March of Time, undated (Box 3, Video 23)
  - Richburg, Alberta H., undated (Box 3, Video 24)
  - Cleselia's Story, undated (Box 4, Video 25)
  - Face to Face Interview (WMC?), undated (Box 4, Video 26)
  - Unidentified ("Film Transfer from 1/2"), undated (Box 4, Video 27)
  - Anniversary, 48th; Marge Dean; March of Time Excerpts, Jan 26, 1984 (Box 4, Video 28)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: Interview, Apr 15, 1982 (Box 4, Video 30)
  - Mitchell, H.L. and Mae Kelly White, Apr 15, 1982 (Box 4, Video 31)
  - Monroe, Evelyn Smith (KCA), Apr 1982 (Box 4, Video 32)
  - Rodgers, Ward and Gardner Jackson, Apr 15, 1982 (Box 4, Video 33)
  - Stith, George [2 copies], Apr 15, 1982 (Box 4, Video 34)
  - Hasiwar, Hank and Fr. Vincent O'Connell, undated (Box 4, Video 35)
  - East, Clay, undated (Box 5, Video 36)
  - Cruz, Philip Vera; George and Leola E. Smith, undated (Box 5, Video 37)
  - Handcox, John L., Steve Remsen, Arthur Churchill, Dr. George McDaniel and Dr. William Tuttle, undated (Box 5, Video 38)
  - Johnson, Clyde, Apr 17, 1982 (Box 5, Video 39)
  - Richburg, Alberta H., undated (Box 5, Video 40)
  - Mitchell, H.L. and Mae Kelly White, Apr 1982 (Box 5, Video 41)
  - Rodgers, Ward, undated (Box 5, Video 43)
  - Handcox, Churchill and Reuther, undated (Box 5, Video 48)
  - Munro, Evelyn Smith, undated (Box 5, Video 52)
  - Rodgers, Ward and Gardner Jackson, Apr 15, 1982 (Box 5, Video 53)
  - Stith, George, Apr 15, 1982 (Box 5, Video 54)
  - East, Clay: Interview on Founding of STFU, undated (Box 5, Video 55)
  - Hasiwar, Hank; Fr. Vincnet O'Connell and Philip Vera Cruz, undated (Box 6, Video 55A)
  - Clark, Deacy Beal and Fanny Booker, undated (Box 6, Video 56)
  - Cruz, Philip Vera; George and Leola E. Smith, undated (Box 6, Video 57)
  - Richburg, Alberta H., undated (Box 6, Video 60)
  - "Our Land Too", undated (Box 6, Video 61)
  - "Poverty in the Land of Plenty", undated (Box 6, Video 61)
  - Anniversary, 48th: H.L. Mitchell and Mae Kelly White, undated (Box 6, Video 71)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: University of Alabama Law School, Mar 19, 1986 (Box 6, Video 72)
  - Chisholm, Shirley, Dec 19, 1986 (Box 6, Video 73)
  - "USSR: Global Assembly", undated (Box 6, Video 74)
  - "UFWA: Wrath of Grapes", undated (Box 6, Video 75)
  - KETC TV Affirmative Action and 50th Anniversary of Sharecroppers Protest, Feb 14, 1989 (Box 6, Video 77)
  - Sharecroppers; [Arvarh?] Strickland, University of Missouri, May 2, 1986 (Box 6, Video 78)
  - Anniversary, 48th; "March of Time", undated (Box 6, Video 79)
  - Mitchell, H.L. (Still Shots), undated (Box 6, Video 80)
  - "Our Land Too" Promotion, undated (Box 6, Video 81)
  - Mitchell, H.L.: Face to Face TV Program, undated (Box 6, Video 82)
  - "The Legacy of Hate in America: The Klu Klux Klan", undated (Box 6, Video 83)
  - "Out of the Past Comes the Future" (Raw Footage), undated (Box 6, Video 84)
  - "Out of the Past Comes the Future"; 48th Anniversary, undated (Box 6, Video 85)
  - Mitchell, H.L: Lander College, Mar 30, 1981 (Box 6, Video 86)
  - "The Making of a Southern Radical / The Origins of the Southern Tenant Farmers Union", undated (Box 6, Video 90)
  - "Dave Burgess", 2007-11-05 (Box Shared Tamiment 013, Cassette 9)